# **David Simmer**

20 years of deep experience in engineering, design, business, and leadership

My engineering and design work has been indispensable to a variety of startups, established businesses, non-profits, and educational institutions across the country.

I'm looking for opportunities to lead people, orchestrate ideas, serve a higher purpose, grow a team, and build something exciting.

# Let's talk soon.

david@simmer.ooo https://simmer.ooo

# Experience

#### Rinse

# Senior Software Engineer, Apr 2018-present

Leading engineering, product design, and agile management on a super-sharp team building the future of dry cleaning and laundry service. Successfully led a redesign and redevelopment of the entire frontend within the first month on the job, increasing signups and active customers by more than 100% year over year. Increasing operational efficiency by designing, building, and deploying updates to internal tools and mobile apps used by employees in the field. Mentoring junior developers, reporting directly to CTO. Continually improving our tooling, our architecture, and our impressiveness as a team.

#### Simmer Inc

# Owner & Creative Developer, 2000-present

Full-stack engineer, designer, project manager, and solo entrepreneur. Orchestrating, designing, prototyping and building clever, good-looking things on the web and in print. Branding and identity design, responsive design, UX and UI consulting, user-friendly content management creation. Managed subcontractors and my own work with Agile principles. Consistently delivered multiple simultaneous projects on deadline, on budget, and with great attention to detail.

# **Qara Partners**

# Founding Partner, 2017-present

Spearheaded the creation of online products and managed in-house design & technology development for a QA/RA consulting firm. Full-stack development, branding, product design, and e-commerce. Developing and selling online products for 21 CFR 820 & ISO 13485 efforts.

#### **Nearest You**

# Senior Technical Advisor, 2017

Provided technical and strategic advice to a rapidly-growing online brand locator startup. Architected key components of brand & location analytics. Improved UI/UX and Rails app structure.

# Skills

#### **Engineering leadership**

Product guidance, project management, mentoring, cross-team communication, architectural decisions, software development methodologies, estimation and budgeting, developer advocacy, business priorities

#### **Full-stack architecture**

APIs, Python, Django, Postgres, Heroku, AWS, microservices, Ruby on Rails, React, Backbone, ES6, JSON, Node, Sass, CSS, HTML, templating languages, mobile platforms

#### Design

UX, motion, interaction, accessibility, typography, color, UI across the device spectrum

# Education

#### Engineering & design

I didn't go to school for CS or design, but picked up engineering skills rapidly as I discovered the web and was delighted by changing the pieces from which it's built. Over the years I've been doing high-quality work in a variety of production environments long enough to know that learning is never done.

#### Previous career

I was on a science track, focused on human biology and physiology in undergrad. I'd thought that becoming a chiropractor was a smart career choice. It wasn't until after completing grad school and starting a practice that I realized the endemic ethical and scientific problems in that profession. I retired my license, sold my practice, and dove headfirst into reinventing my career path. Since then, I've been seeking out ways to use my engineering and design skills to contribute to what excited me in the first place: how humans actually work.



### **Medgineering Inc**

CTO, 2014-2017

Architected, designed, developed, and deployed a quality and regulatory online consultant marketplace called QuickConsult. Singlehandedly built a public MVP, getting us to revenue-positive immediately after launch. Rearchitected v2 on a Rails/Postgres/Dokku stack, laying the groundwork for additional developers to join the team. Familiarized myself with 21 CFR 820 & ISO 13485 to anticipate needs of quality/regulatory clients and consultants. Created and managed branding and communications across our sales and support efforts. Sold the company in 2017.

### **Good Work Group**

Web Development & UX Partner, 2015-present

Full-stack development, design, and technical consulting to assist Good Work Group in making a lasting, positive impact through strategy, creative ideation, storytelling, design, and passion for worthy clients. I led the technical portion of project pitches, landed large-budget work, and managed client communication and meetings.

# **Spring**

Web Developer, 2013-2015

Provided high-performance front end development for various high-profile agency clients and brands. Worked remotely in sync with team members across the Atlantic. My very first project with Spring won accolades for its design and technical aspects.

# **Holmes Corporation**

Product Application Developer, 2008-2015

Designer and developer on a small Agile-based software dev team. Designed and built online educational software on a custom Dojo and Python-based framework, working daily with backend developers, project managers, and marketing/sales staff to support and improve learning products with thousands of concurrent users. Kanban, Selenium, Jenkins CI, BDD/TDD. Independently proposed and completed in-house marketing, design, and ecommerce projects.

# Normandale Community College

Digital Technology Specialist, 1999-2004

Associate webmaster, responsible for new online initiatives, regular website maintenance and upgrades. Advocated for and led a first-of-its-kind in the MnSCU system Section 508 accessibility initiative. Rearchitected and rebuilt the entire college's web platform, developing a complete permissions-enabled CMS (content management system) from scratch, reducing data entry time for academic and marketing departments by 67%. Also provided video production, print design, photography and technology help desk staffing.

Let's talk soon.

david@simmer.ooo https://simmer.ooo

